Looks like we have the best new
open-source coding model and it's by
Alibaba. Not too long ago, the Alibaba
team had introduced the Quen 3 model
series and now they're back again
announcing major updates to it. Now,
especially with the Quen 3 coder, they
came out with a new update with enhanced
terminal task capabilities today as well
as better performance on the terminal
bench. Its coding agent abilities have
been boosted as well as achieving an
impressive score of 69.6. 6 on the sway
bench verified while also showing
stronger safeguards for generating more
secure code. Now on top of this they've
also upgraded their CLI tool code by
adding support for multimodal models as
well as a sub agent system. And from now
on you can even input images while
collaborating with clen code opening up
a whole new dimension for coding
workflows. But that's not all. This
week, Alibaba team has been on fire with
many different model drops. Along with
the launch of the upgraded Quen 3 coder,
they've introduced Quen 3 Max, which
supercharges the entire Quen lineup.
This is Quen's new flagship model, and
it enhances many different capabilities
equipped with tool use and advanced
Aenta capabilities, achieving
nearperfect results on key performance
benchmarks. It's built on massive scale
plus data and backed by relentless
compute scaling in both pre-training as
well as reinforcement learning. So this
Quen 3 Max is just setting a new
standard and it's something that we'll
take a look at alongside with the new
Quen 3 coder. But now going back to the
Quen 3 coder, this new model offers 128K
context window, which is pretty small
compared to other models. And it offers
advanced tool calling as well as
autonomous coding. But in terms of its
pricing structure, it's listed at $1 per
1 million input tokens. And it starts at
$5 for 1 million output tokens. So it
isn't the cheapest in comparison to
other models and it doesn't have a
larger context but in terms of its
coding capabilities it's better than
other open source models for sure. Now
to get started with these models you can
definitely do so through Quen's chatbot
and you also have the ability to access
it through the Alibaba cloud model
studio where you can access their API
keys. But in my opinion I prefer using
Open Router. It is another provider
where you can access the API keys for
all these different models. And say if
you want to get a free API, I definitely
recommend that you use it with Kilo Code
cuz they offer a lot of free credits so
that you can easily get started. They
offer up to $25 worth of free credits
which will get you a lot of usage out of
the Quinn models due to its cheap
pricing. So if you want, you can
definitely easily get started by heading
over to VS Code, your IDE. Any ID works,
but in this case, if it's VS Code, you
can simply install the the Kilo code
extension through the extension tab. And
then you can go over to the Kilo code
settings. And then you can set the model
over here to the new Quen 3 coder. And
then you can just simply go ahead and
search it up. And you're going to be
able to access it directly within Kilo
Code. Within Kilo Code, I'm going to go
ahead and have it first start off by
testing out to create a browserbased OS
that has many features. This is a new
prompt that I'm testing out that I saw
on Twitter. And essentially, this is
something that has the ability to focus
on testing the model's ability to create
different coding components with a lot
of creativity. And you can see that it
has created a thorough plan already as
to how it's going to develop this and
how it's going to code out all the
components of an operating system. So
let's see what it actually ends up
building for us. Since 2011, Zapier has
lit the way towards the future of work.
And on September 25th, they're back with
the Zap Connect 2025, the free virtual
event where AI goes from cool demos to
scalable reality. Expect hands-on
workshops, insider product sessions, and
bigname keynotes like Fox CEO Aaron
Levy, plus Lavar Burton, who will
deliver a keynote on the future of AI in
humanity. You'll also get networking
builder battles and even the chance to
win prizes in the light the way
sweepstake. Want to build an AI workflow
or learn how to start your AI company?
These are different sessions that you
can join virtually. You can also
discover powerful integrations and claim
limited time offers to automate, grow,
and save. And that's not all. Zapier
just dropped an updated Copot, your AI
partner, that can turn a simple idea
into a productionready workflow in
minutes. Plus, don't miss out their
brand new podcast, Agent of Scale, which
is hosted by the Zapier CEO, Wade
Foster, where leaders share unfiltered
lessons on scaling AI across fast
growing companies. But unlike the
podcast, Zap Connect is one day only.
So, make sure you join on September
25th. This is something that I'll leave
links to in the description below so
that you can easily register and get
your free ticket today. Also, thanks to
Zapier for sponsoring today's video.
Zapier lights the way, but will you
follow is the question. So, it looks
like it has finished creating the
browserbased OS and you can see that it
looks pretty nice and in this case it
has created an authentication log to the
web OS. So, I'm going to continue as a
guest and this is actually pretty nice.
You can see that it looks like a pretty
cool operating system. You have the text
editor which is an app that you can
actually write things with. So that's
actually pretty cool. So I can say
something like world of AI and then I
can save that and you can see that the
text has been saved and now I can close
this. This was just one simple app that
it created through the webOS. You can
see there's other things like a web
browser. Uh it doesn't actually work but
you can see that it preconfigured all
these different components like like
creating a file manager or a settings
tab that has all the different features
a part of this app. calculator, which is
pretty cool, text editor, a media
player, as well as an image viewer. So,
overall, it did get this prompt right,
and it looks pretty cool. Next up, we're
going to have the model generate a
butterfly in SVG code. This is a prompt
that we're trying to see how well the
model is in generating SVG code, as well
as focusing on creating symmetry for the
butterfly. So, let's actually go ahead
and copy this SVG code, go over to an
online SVG viewer, and then paste it in.
And there we go. We have a simple
butterfly. Now, it doesn't look the
best, but it did get the main structure
and symmetry right of a butterfly.
Following up with this prompt, I simply
told it to animate it, and it did do a
good job in terms of animating the
butterfly, which is great to see cuz
most open source models actually fail at
this task. Now, that exact same prompt,
I'm going to test it out with the Quen 3
Max to see how well it is in terms of
generating the SG code. So, it looks
like it has finished generating the
code. I'm going to copy it. Go over to
this online SG viewer. This is the
previous generation, but now we're going
to go ahead and paste it in. This is the
new generation with the Quen 3 Max. So,
this does not look like a butterfly. And
unfortunately, it failed at that task,
surprisingly. Next up, I had requested
the Quen 3 coder on generating a SAS
landing page, and this actually looks
pretty cool. It has the new placeholder
and it also has many new features that
you wouldn't see typically with an AI
SAS generated website and in this case
it looks pretty good with the bottom
footer fully configured a pricing tier
that has different gradients and
essentially did a great job with this
generation. So it's great to see that
Quen 3 was able to output good front-end
designs. Next up within Kilo Code, I'm
going to have the Quen 3 coder work on
generating a Minecraft clone from
scratch where it's going to work on
algorithmic reasoning where it's going
to implement the game's physics, the
collision detection that is present
within Minecraft game loops, as well as
different behaviors that the AI coding
model can actually work on. It's going
to also help assess how well it is in
terms of generating all these different
files that we have requested it to work
on, like adding a crafting system, which
is pretty cool. In this case, if it's
able to do this, that would be awesome.
Adding different components of part of
the game and correctly using graphics
input, as well as all of these libraries
to create a functional Minecraft clone.
So, let's see if it's actually able to
do that. So, I just had it generate the
clone and I've just opened it up and it
doesn't look like it has done a good job
in generating it. So, this is actually
kind of unfortunate cuz this does not
look like a Minecraft clone at all. So,
I don't know. The previous generation
that I got from the Quen 3 model was
actually able to do this. Maybe I need
to use a different coding agent. I don't
know what's up. But, it failed at this.
So, it's kind of surprising. Certain
cases it does good. In other cases, it
doesn't, which is something that I
didn't really expect. Something I've
noticed is that this model is really
fast in terms of taking action
generating anything. I simply just told
it to create a crypto trading purp and
it did it pretty quickly and it looks
actually pretty good. It looks a lot
better than what we saw yesterday with
the other DeepSeek V3.1 Terminus model.
And in this case, you can see that
there's different sorts of components
that generated. Now everything works cuz
it's on the web and it has a smaller
context, but in essence, it gets all the
components generated pretty quickly and
it's something that you can rapidly
prototype with better than something
like the Deep Seek V3.1. If you like
this video and would love to support the
channel, you can consider donating to my
channel through the Super Thanks option
below. Or you can consider joining our
private Discord where you can access
multiple subscriptions to different AI
tools for free on a monthly basis, plus
daily AI news and exclusive content,
plus a lot more. But that's basically it
guys for today's video. I'll leave all
these links in the description below so
that you can easily get started with
this new Quen model. But with that
thought, guys, thank you guys so much
for watching. I hope you enjoyed today's
video and got some sort of value. This
is definitely a great model. It's a lot
better than its previous version. In
certain areas it does better and in
certain other cases it doesn't. So, but
with that thought guys, thank you guys
so much for watching. I hope you enjoyed
today's video and got some sort of
value. Make sure you subscribe to the
second channel if you haven't already.
Make sure you join the newsletter, join
the private Discord, follow me on
Twitter, and lastly, make sure you guys
subscribe, turn on notification bell,
like this video, and please take a look
at our previous videos cuz there's a lot
of content that you'll truly benefit
from. But with that thought, guys, have
an amazing day. Spread positivity, and
I'll see you guys fairly shortly. He
suffers.